## VIPLAV DHANDHUKIA

Hyderabad, India | P: +91 9581173078 | viplav.ba@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/viplav24

### **SUMMARY**

I have over 10 years of Professional experience in the areas of capital markets, agriculture. Solutions-driven business analyst with experience leading cross-functional teams in the development, documentation and delivery of process innovations driving the attainment of business goals. Seek opportunities to transform company practices into fresh, cost-effective solutions leading to more efficient operations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Simply Fresh Pvt Ltd. - Hyderabad, India

Manager

Nov 2019 - Present

Business Analyst - Product Owner

- Developed complete **ERP Farm-In-a-Box** solution which comprises order, inventory, resource, sales & production management modules by capturing business requirements. Measurable outcomes-
  - Nearly 20% revenue growth (2019)

- More than 1 lac labour-cost savings p.m.
- Up to 35% in efficiency gains in order execution
- 40% increase in customer churning
- Initialized Operations & Retail Mobile App (Android) for internal stake holders to enhance accountability, adoptability, efficiency & visibility
- Constructed data driven stories for decision making
- Recommended solutions using data driven approach to improve policies, procedure and processes
- Modelled requirements in UML diagrams like use case, activities, test cases to explain the business requirements, and performed unit & quality assurance test at each deliveries, to assure smooth adoption and implementation of the system
- Initiated Gap analysis and implementing solutions through process streamlining and system development & modifications. Major achievement streamlining the Delivery & Invoice Management, which improved accountability by more than 15% on overall sales
- Created an initial product backlog; attend daily scrum meeting, sprint retrospective meeting on regular intervals
  & managing the team
- Accustomed in translating complex business needs into clear and concise BRD/FRD documents
- Designed & conducted more than 150 training sessions for various stake holders at regular intervals for smooth adoption of developed ERP system
- Extracted data using SQL queries for developing dashboards using PowerBI & Tableau
- Contributed & Presented development to the board on various occasions
- · Leading Risk department of the company.

# Karvy Stock Broking Ltd – Hyderabad, India

Manager

July 2014 – Oct 2019

- Conceptualized & modelled web based application **Auto-Trender** & **Option Orion** to provide all the necessary information required at one place, which included general news flows to client's portfolio, developing and enhancing the derivatives & option strategies after thorough research & gap analysis. Measurable outcome-
  - Increase in revenue by 1.5%

- Fall in customer query/complaint by nearly 6%
- Option volume increase by 8%
- Increase in customer traffic on website by 4%
- Elevated as product owner for maximizing the value of the software by adding features and engaging clients
- Developed Internal LMS for advising clients based on request on price discovery. Measurable outcomes
  - Increase in customer retention by 3%
- Increase in Revenue by 0.5%
- Prepared BRD & FRD's after gathering requirements from various stake holders
- Remained interface between different stakeholders regarding development of software functionality across the SDLC (waterfall) & ensures communication flows timely & accurately
- Represented company on various events like Investor awareness programme, brokers and traders training programme
- Presented research view in TV & Print media number of times
- Conducted more than 30 workshops in reputed educational institutions across India

## Transgraph Pvt Ltd. - Hyderabad, India

Analyst

• Gathered requirements from end users, understanding their requirements & documenting it and communicating to the product owner to build **Trans-Risk** software

- Tested the developed model and doing the fit-gap analysis
- Researched & recommended hedging strategies to the clients

#### **LEADERSHIP BOARD**

- Handled farming technology based on AI, IOT, Climate Engineering & Hydroponics
- Represented company in various media to present research based views and articles
- Conducted many workshops in Top Business schools across India and recruited more than 50 candidates
- Worked in various Asset class like Equities, Derivative, Commodities & Agri-Commodities
- Open & clear communicator at all levels, demonstrating ability to cultivate and foster productive working relationship with all the contacts within line of work. Able to inspire & coach multi-functional teams ensuring consistent performance & success
- Skilled problem identifier and trouble-shooter demonstrating business intelligence to accurately assess situational challenges, bridge technology and business goal and transform creative ideas into efficient technical solutions
- Continued self-learning for knowledge, currently pursuing Data Analysis, Machine Learning
- Proficiently organized and facilitated daily scrum meetings, sprint reviews, retrospective meetings, sprint release planning, JAD & brainstorming sessions.
- Created and modified business-facing documentation such as user manuals, solution briefs and functional summaries
- Identified and addressed any impediments to enhance productivity and efficiency

#### **SKILLS**

 Requirement Gathering Analysis

& • Gap Analysis

Risk Management

User Acceptance

KPI Dashboards & Scorecards

• BI, ERP & RDBMS

Project Management

Data Mining & Analytics

Machine Learning Models

Technical: SQL, R, Python, PowerBI, Tableau, MS Visio, Axure RP, Balsamiq, JIRA

Methodologies: Waterfall, Agile Scrum

## **Certifications & Training:**

- Research Analyst Certification Series XV, NISM Mumbai
- Equity Derivative Certification Series VIII, NISM Mumbai
- Financial Modelling Course with NSE India Certification, IMS Pro School
- Masters in Technical & Derivative Analysis under the mentorship of Dr. CK Narayan
- Comprehensive Programme on Equity Research Analysis, BSE Mumbai
- Comprehensive Programme on Technical Research Analysis, BSE Mumbai

## **EDUCATION**

#### INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF BUSINESS ANALYSIS - CANADA

Certified Business Analysis Professional – CBAP (Application approved)

Pursuing Expected Dec 2021

Nov 2012 – June 2014

**AMITY UNIVERSITY - INDIA** 

Aug 2021

Post Graduate Diploma in Business Analytics & Intelligence – 91.85%/100

ICFAI UNIVERSITY Jan 2017

MBA in Finance - CGPA 6.83 / 10